<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arnaud Allera</title><link>https://arn-all.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Arnaud Allera</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://arn-all.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arnaud Allera</title><link>https://arn-all.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arn-all.github.io/about/</guid><description>About me I am a permanent research scientist at ASNR Cadarache since 2024, in charge of studies on steel ageing using advanced simulation methods. I use ideas from condensed matter physics, metallurgy and machine learning to analyze processes happening at the atomic scale🔬 in metals: defect formation, thermally activated process, phase transformations, materials evolution in environment, etc.
Using massively parallel computational methods such as molecular dynamics, I study solid state physics problems at different scales, using both classical and ML-based methods.</description></item><item><title>Blog</title><link>https://arn-all.github.io/blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arn-all.github.io/blog/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://arn-all.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arn-all.github.io/research/</guid><description>Papers Activation entropy of dislocation glide
Arnaud Allera, Thomas D. Swinburne, Alexandra M. Goryaeva, Baptiste Bienvenu, Fabienne Ribeiro, Michel Perez, Mihai-Cosmin Marinica, David Rodney. Nature Communications volume 16, 8367 (2025) arXiv:2410.04813 Neighbors Map: an Efficient Atomic Descriptor for Structural Analysis
Arnaud Allera, Alexandra M. Goryaeva, Paul Lafourcade, Jean-Bernard Maillet, Mihai-Cosmin Marinica. Computational Materials Science 231, 112535, (2024)
arXiv:2307.00978
Github Robust crystal structure identification at extreme conditions using a density-independent spectral descriptor and supervised learning</description></item></channel></rss>